Daniel R. Gregg

Contact

dgregg@une.edu.au

Information daniel.gregg@intersectioninnovations.com

spaniel.boone@gmail.com

 $+61\ 476\ 184\ 905$

Вю

I have over 14 years of experience as a specialist in microeconomic analysis of resource-sector issues, policy evaluation, applied econometric analysis, and experimental methods for economic evaluation (behavioural economics). Working across research and consulting organisations in Australia and Internationally I have led multiple projects involving large teams of technical and non-technical people and with objectives that range across policy evaluation/advice, analysis of economic theory in real-world situations, and the development and implementation of interventions to support rural development/environmental sustainability initiatives.

I am regarded as an international expert on a range of applied data analysis methods and research methods including field experiments, policy evaluation, econometric analysis, and behavioural interventions with wide-ranging publications on these methods and participation on editorial boards/executive boards for academic organisations.

A focus on behavioural factors in decision making, with a strong foundation in decision theory, experimental methods and behavioural interventions, supports an over-arching interest in 'inclusive design' principles for policy and market-based interventions. This focus is also supported by a substantial amount of experience in applied economic methods (time-series, non-market valuation, causal methods) and by a unique capability in web-based programming methods supporting data visualisation, reporting, engagement and innovations for inclusivity outcomes based on digital technologies.

More recently I have begun to apply skills in 'inclusive design' and in data analysis in the field of web-development. I am currently working on developing applications that provide improved outcomes for disadvantaged groups through targeting technologies at reducing barriers to participation in market and social systems for these groups and through reducing the costs for businesses to target larger, but more complex, populations.

Data analysis capabilities

- Endogeneity and selectivity-corrected methods (causal analysis)
- Non-market valuation
- Time-series analysis
- Maximum likelihood, OLS, GMM, GLM and more

TECHNOLOGIES

- Statistical programming: Python, R
- Web-programming: Javascript, Python, Django, Html
- Other: MERN stack, SQL/NoSQL

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Inclusive program design
- Sustainable development/production
- Behavioural interventions and analysis
- Consumer choice and Non-market valuation
- Productivity and Efficiency Analysis (SFA/DEA)
- Environmental Economics

Research CAPABILITIES

- Statistical/Econometric analysis (using R)
- Full-stack programming (Python-Django, MERN)
- Survey design (household analysis, choice experiments, likert-based approaches, impact-evaluation, stated preference methods)
- Laboratory experiments (design, programming, analysis, running)
- Field experiments (design, analysis, running)
- Applied econometrics/data analysis

EDUCATION

Trilogy Education Serviceas & University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia (Australia)

• Web Development Bootcamp, Feb-Aug 2021 Technologies: "Javascript (frontend, backend), React, Express, HTML, CSS" GitHub: Daniel Gregg

Central Queensland University, Rockhampton, Queensland (Australia)

• Ph.D., Natural Resource Economics, Sept. 2015

Thesis Title: "Analysing management decisions in agriculture that impact on natural resources"

Advisors: John Rolfe, Ph.D and Chris O'Donnell, Ph.D

Reviewers: Jean-Paul Chavas, PhD; John Quiggin, PhD and; Céline Nauges, PhD

University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland (Australia)

• B.Natural Resource Economics (Hons. 2A) Dec. 2007

Thesis Title: "Factors influencing the adoption of improved maize varieties in East timor"

Advisor: Rob Cramb, Ph.D

CITATION STATISTICS H index=7 (Scopus); 9 (Google Scholar)

Total citations: 325 (Scopus); 626 (Google Scholar)

Research

Senior Research Fellow (60 Percent FTE)

Jan 2020-current

Business School, University of New England EXPERIENCE

Senior Research Fellow

Jan 2017-Jan 2020

Centre for Global Food and Resources, The University of Adelaide

Feb 2016-Jan 2017 Senior Lecturer (Asst. Prof.) Assoc. Director, Waikato Exp. Econ. Lab Lecturer (Asst. Prof.) May 2015-Jan 2016

School of Economics, The University of Waikato

Senior Research Officer

Jul 2012-Mar 2015

Jul 2015-Jan 2017

School of Business and Informatics, Central Queensland University

Research Officer Aug 2009-Jul 2012

School of Business and Informatics, Central Queensland University

Research Officer Jan 2008-Jun 2009

River Consulting, Townsville, Queensland (Australia)

CONSULTING, COMMERCIAL ACTIVITIES

Co-founder and Director 2019-current, Intersection Traders

Intersection Traders is a smallholder-focused ethical coffee supply chain program operating in Uganda and Australia. The supply chain implemented within this business is derived from economic-theoretic principles with a focus on eliminating contracting costs to create a profitable, inclusive supply chain focusing on working with smallholder coffee farmers whilst enhancing quality-assurance and transpareny. The business has been operating since 2019 and is a proof of concept over the potential to implement smallholder-focused supply chains that deliver high-quality and high returns. Intersection Traders operates both a retail cafe in Adelaide, South Australia and an ethical, inclusive, arabica coffee supply chain operating out of Kapchorwa, Uganda.

ADaPT Systems

ADaPT (Automatic Disbursement and Procurement Tracking) Systems is a supply-chain technology being developed to facilitate the realisation of profitable 'inclusive' supply chains: i.e. supply chains that can profitably target smallholder suppliers with high-value market opportunities. ADaPT works by integrating novel chain-of-custody approaches, based on concepts embodied in blockchain technologies, with a innovations in supply chain organisation, quality assurance and automation of payments. ADaPT seeks to massively reduce supply chain procurement costs, increase supply chain transparency and quality assurance, improve governance and facilitate the implementation of ethical approaches to procurement through integration with smallholder-focused supply chain governance systems and the growing number of tech-based financial tools. ADaPT Systems provides a mechanism through which supply chain enterprises can implement changes to procurement that increase returns to source-country suppliers whilst increasing supply chain efficiency and, additionally, providing a mechanism to assure consumers regarding ethical claims.

Co-Founder and Principle Consultant 2021-current, econ-lab

Econ-lab is a modern economics consulting enterprise that provides internationally recognised research capacity in economic analysis with a focus on rural development and resource economic analysis. Econ-lab consultants use leading economic methods, integrating best-practice theoretical and empirical methods whilst ensuring that projects are robust to peer-review through the use of external review mechanisms. Econ-lab works with clients to determine the best approach to solving problems cognisant of robustness, cost, efficiency and target audiences.

OTHER POSITIONS

Associate Editor 2018-current, Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics

Secretary 2018-2019, Australasian Agricultural and Resource Economists Society

AWARDS

Best post-graduate thesis Best post-graduate thesis Australian Postgraduate Award

AARES 2016 CQ University 2016 2011-2015

REFEREED
JOURNAL
PUBLICATIONS

1. Mead, N., Garbinsky, E. and **Gregg, D.** 2021. "Popping the Positive Illusion of Financial Responsibility Can Increase Personal Savings: Applications in Emerging and Western Marke", *Journal of Marketing*, 85(3): 97-112. Impact Factor 7.8, A* (ERA/ABDC).

- 2. Collard, S., O'Connor, P., Prowse, A., **Gregg, D.** and Bond, A. (2020). "Objectives versus realities: Spatial, temporal, financial and social deficiencies in Australia's public revegetation invetsment model." *Ecological Management and Restoration.* **21**: 35-41. Impact Factor 1.086.
- 3. Hasibuan, M., **Gregg, D.**, and Stringer, R. 2020. "Accounting for diverse risk attitudes in measures of risk perceptions: A case study of climate change risk for small-scale citrus farmers in Indonesia." *Land Use Policy.* **95**. Impact Factor 3.682. A rank (ABDC, ERA)
- 4. Wheeler, S., **Gregg, D.** and Singh, M. 2019. "Understanding the role of social desirability bias and environmental attitudes and behaviour on South Australians' stated purchase of organic foods", *Food Quality and Preference*. **74**: 125-134. Impact Factor 3.65. A rank (ERA).
- 5. Loch, A. and **Gregg, D.** 2018. "Salinity management in the Murray-Darling Basin: a transaction cost study", *Water Resources Research.* **54**(11): 8813-8827. Impact Factor 4.36. A* rank (ABDC,ERA).
- 6. Gregg, D. and Wheeler, S. 2018. "How can we value an environmental asset that very few have visited or heard of? Lessons learned from applying contingent and inferred valuation in an Australian wetlands case study", Journal of Environmental Management. Accepted April 2018. Impact Factor 4.01. A rank (ERA).
- 7. **Gregg, D.** and Rolfe, J. 2018. "Myopia and saliency in renewable resource management", *Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics*, **59**:1-26. Impact Factor 1.826. A rank (ERA, ABDC).
- 8. **Gregg, D.** and Rolfe, J. 2017. "Risk behaviours and grazing land management: A framed experimental investigation of decision making under risk and linkages to range land condition", *Journal of Agricultural Economics*, **86**: 682-709. Impact Factor 1.795 A rank (ERA, ABDC).
- Gregg, D. and Rolfe, J. 2016. "Dynamic decision making and bounded rationality: Review of a framed dynamic decision experiment conducted in the field", Land Use Policy 54: 508-521. Impact Factor 3.682, A rank (ABDC, ERA)
- 10. **Gregg, D.** and Rolfe, J. 2016. "The value of environmental health across conditional efficiency quantiles", *Ecological Economics*, **128**: 44-54. Impact Factor 3.049. A rank (ABDC, ERA)
- 11. Rolfe, J. and **Gregg, D.** 2015. 'Factors affecting adoption of improved management practices in the pastoral industry in Great Barrier Reef catchments", *Journal of Environmental Management*, **157**: 182-193. 1 Citation, Impact Factor 3.507, A rank (ABDC, ERA).
- 12. Greiner, R., Franklin, D. and **Gregg, D.** 2013. "Towards an improved understanding of angler tourism in northern Australia: The 'grunter hunters' of Karumba (Queensland)", *Fisheries Management and Ecology*, **20**: 161-173. 1 Citation, Impact Factor 1.8, B rank (ERA).
- Rolfe, J. and Gregg, D. 2012. "Valuing beach recreation across a regional area: The Great Barrier Reef in Australia", Ocean and Coastal Management,
 69: 282-290. 11 Citations, Impact Factor 1.728.

- 14. **Gregg, D.**, Rolfe, J. 2011. "Identifying sources and trends for productivity growth in Queensland broad-acre beef enterprises", *Animal Production Science*, **52**(1):443-453. 5 Citations, Impact Factor 0.854, A rank (ERA).
- 15. Rolfe, J., **Gregg, D.**, Ivanova, G., Lawrence, R. and Rynne, D. 2011. "The economic contribution of the resources sector by regional areas in Queensland", *Economic Analysis and Policy*, **41**(1): 15-36. 15 Citations, Impact Factor 0.41, C rank (ERA), B rank (ABDC)
- 16. Greiner, R. and **Gregg, D.** 2011. "Farmers' intrinsic motivations, barriers to the adoption of conservation practices and effectiveness of policy instruments: Empirical evidence from northern Australia", *Land Use Policy*, **28**(1): 275-265. Impact Factor 3.682, A rank (ABDC, ERA).
- 17. Greiner, R. and **Gregg, D.** 2010. "Considering recreational catch and harvest in fisheries management at the bio-regional scale", *Fisheries Management and Ecology*, **17**: 336-345. 3 Citations, Impact Factor 1.8, B rank (ERA).

Papers under review

- 1. **Gregg, D.**, and Just, D. "Consumption and income dynamics of the rural poor". Revise and Resubmit, Economic Development and Cultural Change
- 2. Nguyen, D., **Gregg, D.**, Umberger, W. and Zeng, D. "Reconsidering the assumptions underpinning food market modernisation in Vietnam: A critical analysis of urban household retail format choices in relation to food safety, price, and convenience" Submitted to Food Policy (July 2021).

WORKING PAPERS (CLOSE TO SUBMISSION)

- 1. "Inefficiency in the household: A revealed preference study on keeping income private from spouses in rural Uganda" with Arslan, C. and Stringer, R.
- 2. "Livelihood Trajectories with Heterogeneous Technology Sets in Rural India". With Daniel Hill and Shalander Kumar
- "Participation and bidder behaviour in reverse auctions with anticipated regrets and competition uncertainty" With Steven Schilizzi, Sayed Iftekar and Patrick O'Connor.
- 4. "Nonlinear patterns in the relation between productivity and farm size in the context of Indian land policies" With Anupama GV and Thomas Falk.
- 5. "Drivers of participation in higher cost and lower value coffee markets: A case study of parchment market participation in eastern Uganda from an asymmetric information and credit constraints perspective" with Cansin Arslan.

Teaching

Agricultural Trade (Masters)	2015
Agricultural Trade (Undergraduate)	2016
Introduction to Microeconomics (MBA)	2016
Trends and Issues in the Global Food System (Masters)	2019

WORKSHOPS DELIVERED

Intermediate Econometrics in R

February 2016

Referee Activities

Agricultural Economics, Ecological Economics, Climatic Change, Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics, New Zealand Economic Papers, Food Security

VISITING ICRISAT 2018-2019 (3 months several visits)

SCHOLAR SLU (Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences) Feb-Apr 2015 SLU (Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences) Feb-Apr 2014

Stirling University

November 2011

Seminar Do we need to go further in analysing and intervening in value chain upgrading?

PRESENTATIONS October 2020

University of New England

Consumption and income dynamics of the rural poor

July 2019

Wageningen University

Output quality incentives under aggregation and monitoring failure in smallholderdominated coffee supply chains

July 2019

Gottingen University

Heterogeneity in wealth dynamics in India

July 2018

University of Adelaide

Heterogeneity in wealth dynamics in India

July 2018

University of Adelaide

Market integration, correlation aversion and interventions supporting poor farmers in Rajasthan

April 2016

University of Otago

The value of environmental health March 2015

SLU (Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences)

Complexity Induced Myopia October 2014

University of Queensland

Complexity Induced Myopia September 2014

University of Otago

Complexity Induced Myopia June 2014

Monash University

Complexity Induced Myopia March 2014

SLU (Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences)

Ecological dynamics in agricultural production April 2014

SLU (Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences)

Projects Sustainability standards and certification: A review of concepts and international

practices for Australian agro-food enterprises and industries.

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$15,000 AUD

Funding body: Australian Farm Institute

Considering the potential for adaptive management to achieve improved economic, environmental, social, and cultural outcomes for Aboriginal grazing enterprises and associated stakeholders in the Fitzroy River (Martuwarra) area of northern Western

Australia.

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$10,000 AUD

Funding body: Pew Charitable Trusts

Agricultural Marketing Strategy for Shared Prosperity in Agro-food Development.

Position: Co-PI

Project value: \$130,000 (USD)

Funding body: World Bank, Malaysia

Agricultural Policy Research to Support Natural Resource Management in Indonesia's Upland Landscapes (INDOGREEN) (University of Adelaide, 2018-2022).

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$1,600,000 (AUD)

Funding body: Australian Centre for International Agricultural Research

Developing value chain innovation platforms to improve food security in east and southern Africa (University of Adelaide, 2015-2019).

Position: Principal Investigator (Australian component)

Project value: \$2,999,000 (USD)

Funding body: Australian Centre for International Agricultural Research

Designing for Uncertainty in Conservation Auctions - sub-contract to conduct experimental studies (University of Adelaide, 2018).

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$26,000 (AUD)

Funding body: University of Western Australia

Valuing Parrakie Wetlands (University of Adelaide, 2016).

Position: Co-Investigator Project value: \$10,000 (AUD)

Funding body: Parrakie Wetland Owners

Two 'wrongs' can make a 'right': Behavioural irrationality as an evolutionary response to bounded rationality (University of Waikato, 2015).

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$40,000 (NZD)

Funding body: Waikato University Strategic Investment Fund

Seed funding to establish a productivity research centre at the University of Waikato

(University of Waikato, 2015). Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$6,000 (NZD)

Funding body: Waikato Management School

Considering optimal management of common grazing resources in the Rajasthan area of India: Scoping and initial survey (University of Waikato, 2015).

Position: Principal Investigator Project value: \$13,000 (NZD)

Funding body: Waikato Management School

The value of recreational angling in stocked impoundment permit scheme dams in Queensland (Central Queensland University, 2012).

Position: Investigator Project value: \$127,431.82

Funding body: Queensland Department of Agriculture, Fisheries and Forestry The

meeting place: Estimating the economic value of ground cover and sustainable production practices to broad acre grazing enterprises (Central Queensland University,

2011).

Position: Principal Investigator

Project value: \$39,217

Funding body: Fitzroy Basin Association

Develop a Water Quality metric for Melbourne Water (Central Queensland Uni-

versity, 2010).

Position: Investigator Project value: \$72,628

Funding body: Melbourne Water

Water quality impacts of recreation activity in the Great Barrier Reef Marine Park

(River Consulting, 2008). Position: Principal Investigator

Project Value: \$42,800

Funding body: Great Barrier Reef Marine Park Authority

Review of the Sugar Industry Reform Package (River Consulting, 2008).

Position: Investigator Project value: \$139,000

Funding body: Australian Government Department of Agriculture Forestry and

Fisheries.

Participation in conservation covenants and conservation management agreements

by NT pastoralists (River Consulting, 2008).

Position: Investigator Project value: \$19,800

Funding body: Natural Resource Management Board, NT.